Register of the Gottfried Haberler papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Gottfried Haberler papers
1900-1998
95048
Hoover Institution Archives
113 manuscript boxes, 1 cubic foot box, 9 oversize box (70.8 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, printed matter, photographs, slides, and memorabilia relating to economic theory, and especially to laissez-faire economics and associated concepts of liberty.
Haberler, Gottfried, 1900-1995
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1995.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1900: Born, Puckersdorf, Austria-Hungary
1923: Graduated from University of Vienna with a degree in Law
1925: Graduated from University of Vienna with a degree in Economics
1927: Visited major U.S. universities as a Rockefeller Fellow
1927: Authored The Meaning of Index Numbers
1928: Obtained Habilitation from University of Vienna
1932: Authored Money and the Business Cycle
1933: Authored The Theory of International Trade
1936: Joined the faculty of the Economics Department at Harvard
1937: Authored Prosperity and Depression
1963: Appointed President of the American Economic Association
1971: Appointed Resident Scholar of the American Enterprise Institute
1995: Died, Washington, D.C.
Scope and Contents of Collection
Consisting of correspondence, speeches and writings, writings by others, publications, photographs, and slides related to economic theory, and especially to laissez-faire economics, the Haberler papers are comprised of three increments of materials; the third and final increment was received in 1995 after Haberler’s death. Although the three increments were received separately, there is considerable overlap between them in terms of the types of materials they contain and the themes or individuals represented in them.
The first increment (boxes 1-57 and 123) is comprised of correspondence, speeches and writings, writings by others, and biographical materials. The correspondence is arranged chronologically, alphabetically, and thematically.
The second increment (boxes 58-67) is comprised of biographical materials, correspondence, speeches and writings, writings by others, printed matter, and materials related to various conferences attended by Haberler. The Biographical file of the second increment includes curriculum vitae, speeches and articles related to Haberler’s life, and interviews. The Correspondence series of the second increment is arranged alphabetically, and contains correspondence between Haberler and other economists dating from the later part of his career (1971-1991).
The Speeches and Writings series of the second increment is comprised of various drafts of articles and books written by Haberler, as well as correspondence related to the publishing of those works. The Writings by Others series contains published copies and unpublished drafts of articles written by other contemporary economists. The Printed Matter series of the second increment is comprised of various political and economic publications including newsletters, magazines, government reports, and clippings.
The third increment (boxes 68-112) is comprised of biographical materials, correspondence, speeches and writings, writings by others, printed matter, photographs, and slides. The Biographical File of the third increment is comprised of expired passports, articles and speeches related to Haberler’s life, as well as address and telephone directories. The Correspondence series of the third increment is arranged alphabetically and contains correspondence between Haberler and other economists dating primarily from the early part of his career from the 1920s to the 1940s. Notable among these are considerable collections of correspondence between Haberler and Hayek, Machlup, Friedman, and Keynes discussing economic issues and conferences. Also included in this series, is a substantial collection of correspondence between Haberler and his parents dating from the 1920s discussing Haberler’s travel throughout America and Europe during his time as a Rockefeller Scholar.
The Writings by Others series of the third increment contains published copies and unpublished drafts of articles written by other contemporary economists. The Printed Matter series of the third increment contains various publications, including newsletters and magazines published by the American Enterprise Institute, the von Mises Institute and the Cato Institute.
The Photographs series of the third increment contains photographs taken at various conferences and meetings attended by Haberler, as well as a large collection of personal photographs and slides taken on vacation in Europe, Africa, Asia, and the United States.
Friedman, Milton, 1912-2006; Hayek, Friedrich A. von (Friedrich August), 1899-1992.; Machlup, Fritz,; Economics.; Economists.; Laissez-faire.; Liberty.; Von Mises, Ludwig, 1881-1973.
- Chronological file (mainly outgoing letters)
  - 1990-1995 (Box 1)
  - 1986-1989 (Box 2)
  - 1982-1985 (Box 3)
  - 1978-1981 (Box 4)
- Alphabetical file (mainly correspondence) (Box 5)
  - Albert Universitatsbuchhandlung
  - Alchian, Armen A.
  - Allen (George) & Unwin (Publishers)
  - Allen, Loring
  - American Austrian Foundation
  - American Economist
  - Andreae, C. A.
  - Argentine award ceremony, 1991
  - Arndt, Helmut
  - Arndt, Sven W.
  - Aschinger, Franz
  - Baffi, Paolo (Box 6)
  - Baier, Robert
  - Balassa, Bela
  - Baldwin, Robert E.
  - Banca Commerciale Italiana
  - Baroody, William J.
  - Bartley, Robert
  - Bartley, W. W., III
  - Bauer, Peter
  - Baur, Georg
  - Beckerman, Wilfred (Box 7)
  - Beltran, Lucas
  - Bergsten, C. Fred
  - Bernis, Gerard de
  - Bernstein, Edward M.
  - Besters, Hans
  - Bhagwati, Jagdish
  - Blumenthal, W. Michael
  - Bohm, Stephan
  - Bombach, Gottfried
  - Bos, Dieter
  - Bosch, Alfred
  - Bovet, Eric D.
  - Brems, Hans
  - Bress, Ludwig
  - Briefs, Godfrey E.
  - Brookings Institution
  - Brown, Sidney
  - Browne, Martha Steffy
  - Brunner, Karl (Box 8)
  - Brunsdale, Anne
  - Brusatti, Alois
  - Bulhoes, Octavio
  - Burmeister, Harald
  - Burns, Arthur F.
  - Cables and telegrams
  - Cabral, Martim L.
  - Camaiti, Romolo
  - Cambridge Trust Company
  - Camu, Louis
  - Carli, Guido
  - Caves, Richard E.
  - Ceriani, Luigi
  - Chamber of Commerce, Madrid, Spain
  - Chamber of Commerce of the U.S.A.
  - Chipman, John S. (Box 9)
  - Chu, David S. C.
  - Clark, Peter B.
  - Clement, Werner
  - Cooper, Richard N.
  - Corbet, Hugh
  - Corden, W. M.
  - Cosmos Club
  - Council of Economic Advisers
  - Cowles Foundation for Research in Economics
  - Crank letters
  - Cunha, Luiz Roberto Azevedo
  - Currier, Elizabeth B.
  - Curtis, Thomas B.
  - Curzon, Gerard
  - DeMuth, Christopher C. (Box 10)
  - Denver meeting, National Association of Business Economics, 1974
  - De Vries, Margaret
  - De Vries, Rimmer
  - Donges, J. B.
  - Dorn, James A.
  - Dornbusch, Rudiger
  - Dunlop, John T.
  - Earhart Foundation
  - Ebeling, Richard M.
  - Economica
  - Economists' Bookshop
  - Eichengreen, Barry
  - Eichler, Ned
  - Eizenga, Wietze
  - Eldridge, Douglas H.
  - Ellis, Howard S.
  - Emminger, Otmar (Box 11)
  - Enke, Stephen
  - Erdilek, Asim
  - Erndl, Wolfgang
  - Eucken (Walter) Institut
  - Faber, Malte
  - Fand, David I.
  - Fauvel, Luc
  - Feldstein, Martin
  - Fellner, William J.
  - Fels, Gerhard
  - Fernandes, Roberto M.
  - Feuchtmuller, Wolfgang
  - Fischer (Gustav) Verlag
  - Fleisig, Heywood
  - Foley, James J.
  - Fong, Shan-Kwei
  - Forbes Magazine
  - Foundation Francisco Marraquin
  - Frankel, Paul H. (Box 12)
  - Franzsen, D. G.
  - Friedman, Benjamin M.
  - Friedman, Milton
  - Fritsch, Bruno
  - Furth, J. Herbert
  - Furth, John F.
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth
  - Gantner, Manfried
  - Gardner, Walter R.
  - Gerber, Beat
  - German award ceremony, 1978
  - Gerschenkron, Alexander
  - Giersch, Herbert (Box 13)
  - Group of Thirty
  - Gudin, Eugenio
  - Gutowski, Armin
  - Haag, John (Box 14)
  - Haberler, Gottfried
    - Personal
    - 85th birthday, 1985
    - 90th birthday, 1990 (Box 15)
  - Habsburg, Otto von
  - Halberg, Franz
  - Hanke, Steve H.
  - Hansen, Alvin H.
  - Hanson, James
  - Harberger, Arnold C. (Box 16)
  - Hardt, John P.
  - Harris, Ralph
  - Harris, Seymour E.
  - Harrod, Sir Roy F.
  - Harvard University
  - Hawtrey, Sir Ralph
  - Hayek, Friedrich A. von
  - Heilperin, Michael A.
  - Heller, H. Robert
  - Henderson, David
  - Henderson, Elizabeth
  - Hermens, Ferdinand A.
  - Hexner, Ervin P.
  - Higgonet, Rene P. (Box 17)
  - Hildebrand, George H.
  - Hillsdale College
  - Hinshaw, Randall
  - Hirschman, Albert O.
  - Hodge (William) and Company
  - Hoffmann, Harriet
  - Hogan, Warren P.
  - Holzman, Franklyn D.
  - Honorarium
  - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace
  - Houthakker, Hendrik S.
  - Hudeczek, Carl
  - Hufbauer, Gary
  - Hunold, Albert
  - Hutchison, Terence W.
  - Ikle, Max
  - Institute for Humane Studies (Box 18)
  - Institute for International Economics
  - Institute of Economic Affairs
  - International Economic Association
  - International Monetary Fund
  - Invoices
  - Irvine, Reed J.
  - Jackel, Ottilie
  - Japan (U.S.-) Young Political Leaders Exchange Program
  - Javits, Jacob K.
  - Jay, Peter
  - Johnson, Harry G.
  - Johr, Walter Adolf
  - Kafka, Alexandre (Box 19)
  - Kamitz, Reinhard
  - Kasper, Wolfgang
  - Katz, Lorie
  - Katz, Samuel I.
  - Kaufmann, Felix (Box 20)
  - Kellner, Irwin L.
  - Kemmerer, Donald L.
  - Kenen, Peter B.
  - Keran, Michael
  - Keuschnigg, Christian
  - Keynes, John Maynard
  - Kindleberger, Charles P.
  - Klein, Guillermo Walter
  - Klein, Philip A.
  - Koo, Anthony Y. C.
  - Koren, Stephan
  - Krauss, Melvyn B.
  - Kreisky, Bruno
  - Krueger, Anne O.
  - Krul, Nicolas
  - Kung, Emil
  - L (Box 21)
  - Laffer, Arthur B.
  - Lal, Deepak
  - Lambsdorff, Otto Graf
  - Lamot, Jean-Louis (Box 123)
  - Lehrman, Lewis E.
  - Leijonhufvud, Axel
  - Leijonhufvud, Earlene Craver
  - Leontief, Wassily
  - Leroy, Vely
  - Leube, Kurt R. (Box 22)
  - Leutwiler, Fritz
  - Linder, Willy
  - Lindsay, Michael
  - Link, Max E.
  - Loschner, Ernst
  - Lubbert, Jens
  - Lundberg, Erik
  - Lutz, Friedrich A.
  - McClam, Warren D. (Box 23)
  - McCracken, Paul W.
  - Machlup, Fritz
  - MacLaury, Bruce K.
  - McLure, Charles E., Jr.
  - Mailing lists
  - Mallakh, Ragaei El
  - Maltsev, Yuri N.
  - Marer, Paul
  - Marimo, Guido Zerilli
  - Marz, Eduard
  - Mast, Hans J.
  - Mathews, James
  - Matlock, Clifford C.
  - Meade, James E. (Box 24)
  - Meltzer, Allan H.
  - Menger, Karl
  - Mering, Otto von
  - Mintz, Ilse
  - Mobil Oil Corporation
  - Mock, Alois
  - Molsberger, Josef
  - Monroe, Wilbur F.
  - Mont Pelerin Society (Box 25)
  - Moore, Geoffrey H.
  - Morgenstern, Oskar
  - Morrison, Robert S.
  - Muller-Groeling, Hubertus
  - Mundell, Robert A.
  - Murphy, Ernest L.
  - Murphy, J. Carter
  - Musgrave, Richard A.
  - National Science Foundation
  - Neuberger, Egon (Box 26)
  - New York Times
  - Newspaper clippings
  - Nishiyama, Chiaki
  - Nobel Symposium
  - Nomura Research Institute
  - North-Holland Publishing Company
  - Notel, Rudolf
  - Nussbaumer, Adolf
  - Officer, Lawrence
  - Ohlin, Bertil
  - Ohlin, Goran
  - Olivera, Julio H. G.
  - Opie, Redvers
  - Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development
  - Panas, Eustace G. (Box 27)
  - Papandreou, Andreas G.
  - Papi, Giuseppe Ugo
  - Per Jacobsson Foundation
  - Perlman, Mark
  - Pfusterschmid, H.
  - Plan, Edgar
  - Platzer, Wilfried
  - Polak, Jacques J.
  - Pollack, Gerald A.
  - Popper, Karl
  - Pribram, Karl
  - Price, Don K.
  - Probst, Raymond
  - Proxmire, William
  - Publications agreements
  - Raffer, Kunibert (Box 28)
  - Rasminsky, Louis
  - "Rational Expectations" paper, 1980
  - Reading lists
  - Reagan, Ronald
  - Redler, Richard
  - Reuss, Henry S.
  - Richter, J. Hans
  - Richter, Rudolf
  - Rio de Janeiro lectures, 1963
  - Ritter, Friedrich
  - Robbins, Lionel
  - Robinson, E. A. G.
  - Rockefeller, David
  - Roosa, Robert V.
  - Royal Economic Society
  - Rueff, Jacques
  - Russel, Robert R.
  - Rutledge, John
  - Ruyter, Hans Michael
  - Ryrie, William S.
  - Salant, Walter S. (Box 29)
  - Salin, Edgar
  - Samuels, L. H. (Box 30)
  - Samuelson, Paul A.
  - Schefold, B.
  - Scheithauer, Max
  - Schiff, Eric
  - Schiltknecht, Kurt
  - Schlesinger, Helmut
  - Schlesinger, James R.
  - Schmidt, Emerson P. (Box 31)
  - Schmidt, G.
  - Schmidt, Wilson E.
  - Schmitz, Wolfgang
  - Schneider, Erich
  - Scholl, Franz
  - Schumpeter, Joseph
  - Schurer, Wolfgang
  - Schweizer Monatshefte
  - Scitovsky, Tibor (Box 32)
  - Seeger, Charles M.
  - Seidel, Hans
  - Seldon, Arthur
  - Seuss, Wilhelm
  - Shih, Chien-sheng
  - Shultz, George P.
  - Simon, Julian L.
  - Simon, Michael
  - Simon, William E.
  - Singh, Janardan Prasad
  - Sobotka, Dieter
  - Socher, Karl
  - Sohmen, Egon
  - Solomon, Anthony M. (Box 33)
  - Solomon, Elinor H.
  - Solomon, Robert
  - Spitaller, Erich
  - Springer-Verlag
  - St. Martin's Press
  - Starlinger, RoseMarie
  - Stein, Herbert
  - Stem, Carl H.
  - Stevens, Sir John
  - Stigler, George J.
  - Stolper, Wolfgang F.
  - Streeten, Paul P.
  - Sugioka, Michio (Box 34)
  - Svyrud, Donald E.
  - Swedberg, Richard
  - Swoboda, Alexander K.
  - Taiwan conference, 1972
  - Takeda, Shozo
  - Tamanoi, Yoshiro
  - Taormina conference, 1971
  - Taquey, Charles H.
  - Templeton, Kenneth S., Jr.
  - Thiel, Elke
  - Tintner, Gerhard
  - Town Meeting, National, Washington, D.C., 1979
  - Treasury Department
  - Triffin, Robert
  - Trilateral economic conference, Tokyo, 1975
  - Tsuru, Shigeto (Box 35)
  - Tugendhat, Albert
  - Tuller, J. D.
  - Tullock, Gordon
  - Vanek, Jaroslav
  - Van Sickle, John V.
  - Vaubel, Roland
  - Veit, Otto
  - Viner, Jacob
  - Von Mises, Ludwig
  - Walker, Charls E. (Box 36)
  - Wall Street Journal
  - Wallich, Christine
  - Wallich, Henry C.
  - Walter, Norbert
  - Ware, Richard A.
  - Washington Post
  - Watrin, Christian
  - Weber, Wilhelm
  - Weizsacker, C. C. von
  - Wijkman, Per Magnus (Box 37)
  - Willett, Thomas D.
  - Willgerodt, Hans
  - Williamson, John
  - Wilson, Thomas
  - Winterberger, Gerhard
  - Winton, J. R.
  - Witteveen, H. Johannes
  - Wright, David McCord
  - Wright, William E.
  - Zahar, Jorge (Box 38)
  - Zeisel, Hans
  - Zolotas, Xenophon
  - Zombanakis, Minos A.
- Publications file (mainly correspondence re)
  - Collected Essays
  - "The Demise of Communism and the German Question"
  - Foreword to Wolfgang Stolper biography of Joseph Schumpeter (Box 39)
  - "Gasoline Tax, etc."
  - "The International Monetary System--Once Again"
  - Italian translations
  - Japanese translations
  - Kaufmann (Felix) songbook project (Box 40)
  - "Liberal and Illiberal Development Policy"
  - "Liberal and Illiberal Trade Policy" (Box 41)
  - The Liberal Economic Order
  - Pioneers in Development (Box 42)
  - "The Political Economy of Regional Blocs"
  - Prosperity and Depression
  - Review of Joseph Schumpeter, Politische Reden
  - Selected Essays
  - "The World Economy and the International Monetary System in the Interwar Period"
- Bibliographies
- Biographical data and photographs (Box 43)
- Cato Institute conference, 1988
- Correspondence, 1940s
- Monetary integration
- New international economic order
- Personal folder (mainly correspondence)
- Target zones (Box 44)
- Miscellany (reprints, other printed matter, addresses, and calling cards)
- Chronological file (mainly writings by Haberler and correspondence re them) (Box 45)
  - Conference in Freiburg, 1973
  - "The Case against Capital Controls for Balance of Payments Reasons,", 1973
  - "The Future of the International Monetary System,", 1974
  - "Thoughts on Inflation,", 1974
  - Discussion paper of Haberler and John P. Hardt, 1974
  - "Some Currently Suggested Explanations and Cures for Inflation,", 1975
  - "Stagflation,", 1975
  - Remarks, Japan-U.S. Assembly meeting, 1975
  - Remarks, First National Bank of Chicago symposium, 1975
  - "Depression and Inflation on Spaceship Earth,", 1975
  - Discussion paper for Dallas conference, 1975
  - "Oil, Inflation, Recession and the International Monetary System,", 1975
  - "World Inflation and World Recession,", 1975
  - "Marktwirtschaft als Aufgabe,", 1975
  - "How Important Is Control over International Reserves?", 1976
  - "Survey of Circumstances Affecting the Location of Production and International Trade as Analyzed in the Theoretical Literature,", 1976
  - Review of The Monetary Approach to the Balance of Payments, 1976
  - Remarks, AEI-Treasury Conference on Flexible Exchange Rates, 1976
  - "John Marcus Fleming,", 1976
  - "The Problem of Stagflation,", 1976
  - William Fellner, "Money Supply and the Budget,", 1977
  - "Modern Challenges to a Liberal International Economic Order,", 1977
  - "The International Monetary System after Jamaica and Manila,", 1977 (Box 46)
  - Review of W. M. Corden, Inflation, Exchange Rates, and the World Economy, 1977
  - "Trade Deficit and the Floating Dollar,", 1978
  - "The State of the World Economy and the International Monetary System,", 1978
  - "The Present Economic Malaise,", 1979
  - "Austria's Economic Development after the Two World Wars,", 1979
  - "Flexible Exchange Rate Theories and Controversies Once Again,", 1979
  - "The Great Depression of the 1930s,", 1979
  - "Notes on Rational and Irrational Expectations,", 1979
  - "Alexander Gerschenkron,", 1979 (Box 47)
  - "Schumpeter's Capitalism, Socialism and Democracy after Forty Years,", 1980
  - American Enterprise Institute Conference on the Political Economy of France, 1980
  - "The Dollar in the World Economy,", 1980
  - Otmar Emminger, speech, 1980
  - American Enterprise Institute Conference on the International Monetary System, 1980
  - "The World Economy, Macroeconomic Theory and Policy,", 1980 (Box 48)
  - "Inflation and Incomes Policy,", 1981
  - Miscellany, 1981
  - "The Economic Malaise of 1980,", 1981
  - "Schumpeter's Capitalism, Socialism and Democracy after Forty Years," Japanese version, 1981
  - "Alvin H. Hansen,", 1981
  - "The World Financial Structure,", 1981
  - "Austria's Economic Development,", 1981 (Box 49)
  - "Mises's Private Seminar,", 1981
  - Conference on Trade Policy in the Eighties, 1982
  - "Vera and Friedrich Lutz,", 1982
  - Pacific Institute for Public Policy Research paper, 1982
  - "Inflation and Incomes Policy,", 1982
  - Trade Policy Research Centre report, 1982
  - "The International Monetary System and the State of the World Economy,", 1983
  - "The International Monetary System in the World Recession,", 1983
  - "William Fellner: In Memoriam,", 1983
  - Comments on trade policy in the, 1980s, 1983 (Box 50)
  - "Theory as a Tool of Policy" (re John Maynard Keynes), 1983
  - Cato Institute conference, 1983
  - Statement, "Pre-Williamsburg" International Monetary Conference, 1983
  - "The Slowdown of the World Economy and the Problem of Stagflation,", 1983
  - Dartmouth Review interview, 1984
  - "International Issues Raised by Criticisms of the U.S. Budget Deficits,", 1984
  - "Methods of Harmonizing Resources and the Demand for Resources in the Western Countries,", 1985
  - Foreword to Joseph Schumpeter, Beitrage zur Sozialokonomik, 1985 (Box 51)
  - Comment on Michael Bordo and Anna Schwartz paper, 1985
  - "Incomes Policies and Inflation" postscript, 1985
  - Printed matter, 1985
  - Sven Herner correspondence, 1985-1986
  - "The International Monetary System,", 1986
  - "Markt koordiniert besser,", 1986
  - Remarks, Institute for International Economics, 1986
  - "The World Economy,", 1986 (Box 52)
  - "Hayek's 'Theory of the Business Cycle' Revisited,", 1986
  - "Further Thoughts on International Policy Coordination,", 1987
  - International Trade and Economic Development, 1987
  - "The International Monetary System,", 1987
  - Helmut Schlesinger, "Economic Policy Coordination and the Market Mechanism,", 1987 (Box 53)
  - "Strategic Trade Policy and the New International Economics,", 1987
  - "Wage and Price Rigidities, Supply Restrictions, and the Problem of Stagflation,", 1987
  - "The International Monetary System and Proposals for International Policy Coordination," including Rolf-Dieter Grass correspondence, 1987
  - "Postscript: How Not to Set Exchange Rates,", 1987
  - "The Great Depression of the 1930s,", 1987
  - "Liberal and Illiberal Trade Policy,", 1987
  - Wolfgang F. Stolper correspondence, 1988 (Box 54)
  - "International Trade and Economic Development,", 1988
  - "The Slowdown of the World Economy and the Problem of Stagflation,", 1988
  - Foreword to Analyzing Modern Business Cycles (Geoffrey Moore Festschrift), 1988
  - Comments on Jacob A. Frenkel and Morris Goldstein paper, 1988
  - Otto von Habsburg, "The Geopolitical Significance of Austria for Europe's Future,", 1988 (Box 55)
  - Evelyn von Wieser correspondence and writings, 1988
  - "Reflections on Hayek's Business Cycle Theory,", 1988
  - "The International Monetary System, the European Monetary System (EMS) and a Single European Currency in a 'Single European Market,'", 1988
  - "A Tribute to Bela [Balassa],", 1989
  - "Profile" (re American Enterprise Institute journal American Enterprise), 1989
  - Helmut Schlesinger birthday celebration, 1989 (Box 56)
  - "The State of the World Economy,", 1989
  - "The U.S. Budget Deficit and the Strong Dollar,", 1989
  - "International Trade and Economic Development,", 1989
  - Letter to the editor, Wall Street Journal, (with Jeremy Fand), 1989
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Post, (with Jeremy Fand), 1989
  - "What Happened to the Business Cycle?", 1990
  - Charles P. Kindleberger birthday celebration, 1990
- Curriculum vitae
- Bibliography
- Examination questions
- Invoices (Box 57)
- Task Force on U.S. Balance of Payments Policies to the President-Elect report and correspondence, 1968-1969
- Exchange control correspondence
- Speeches and writings
  - Comments on paper by Professors Shimano and Triffin
  - Comments on "United States Economic Relations with the Developing World"
  - "Inflation and the Declining Dollar"
  - "Macro and Micro Interdependence under Fixed Rates and Floating"
  - "The Market Economy as a Challenge"
  - "Methods of Harmonizing Resources and the Demand for Resources in the Western Countries"
  - "A Recycling Proposal"
  - "The World Economy and the International Monetary System in the Interwar Period"
  - Miscellany
  - Reprints
- Josef Molsberger, "How Floating Has Worked"
- Biographical file II, 1980-1988
  - Curriculum Vitae and contact information, 1988 (Box-folder 58: 1)
  - Interviews with Gottfried Haberler, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 58: 2)
  - "The New Palgrave Dictionary" entry on Gottfried Haberler, with related correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 58: 3-4)
  - Speeches and articles about Gottfried Haberler, 1980-1987 (Box-folder 58: 5-7)
- Correspondence II, 1978-1991
  - From Kenadjian, Berdj to Jeane J. Kirkpatrick, 1987 (Box-folder 58: 8)
  - From Koo, Anthony Y.C. to Robert Bolick, 1983 (Box-folder 58: 9)
  - From McCracken, Paul W. to Godfrey Briefs, 1988 (Box-folder 58: 10)